Guide to the Yale College Student Records Concerning Attendance, Residence, and Discipline
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale College student records concerning attendance, residence, and discipline
1801-1965
RU 208
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
80.25
(57 boxes, 2 folio folders)
The records consist of administrative files, reports, and correspondence documenting activities and the operations of the Yale College registrar. Included are student files and grade books, entrance cards, room assignments, and attendance records.
Yale College (1887- )
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-F (YRG 9-F), Yale College student records.
Conditions Governing Access
Access is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative files, reports, and correspondence documenting activities and the operations of the Yale College registrar. Included are student files and grade books, entrance cards, room assignments, and attendance records.
College registrars; College students; Yale College (1718-1887); Yale College (1887- ); Yale University -- Students
- Appointments and premiums, 1817-1891; Accession 19ND-A-451
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  Bound volume noting commencement appointments such as valedictorians and orators and winners of scholarships and awards.
  - Appointments and Premiums [bound volume], 1817-1891 (Box 1)
- Matriculation books for the Classes of 1805-1862, 1801-1862; Accession 19ND-A-452
  Four bound volumes.
  - Matriculation book for Classes of 1805-1841, 1801-1841 (Box 1)
  - Class register for Classes of 1849-1862, 1845-1862 (Box 1)
  - Matriculation register, 1836-1854 (Box 2)
  - Signatures of Classes, 1836-1876, 1832-1876 (Box 2)
- Student attendance books, 1815-1830, 1887-1928; Accession 1934-A-003
  - 1815-1830, 1887-1895 (Box 1)
  - 1896-1897 (Box 2)
  - 1898-1899 (Box 3)
  - 1900 (Box 4)
  - 1901 (Box 5)
  - 1902 (Box 6)
  - 1903 (Box 7)
  - 1904 (Box 8)
  - 1905 (Box 9)
  - 1906 (Box 10)
  - 1907 (Box 11)
  - 1907 (Box 12)
  - 1908 (Box 13)
  - 1908 (Box 14)
  - 1909 (Box 15)
  - 1909 (Box 16)
  - 1910 (Box 17)
  - 1910 (Box 18)
  - 1911 (Box 19)
  - 1911 (Box 20)
  - 1912 (Box 21)
  - 1912 (Box 22)
  - 1913 (Box 23)
  - 1913 (Box 24)
  - 1914 (Box 25)
  - 1914 (Box 26)
  - 1915 (Box 27)
  - 1915 (Box 28)
  - 1916 (Box 29)
  - 1916 (Box 30)
  - 1917 (Box 31)
  - 1918 (Box 32)
  - 1918-1919 (Box 33)
  - 1919 (Box 34)
  - 1920 (Box 35)
  - 1920 (Box 36)
  - 1921 (Box 37)
  - 1921 (Box 38)
  - 1922 (Box 39)
  - 1922-1923 (Box 40)
  - 1924-1925 (Box 41)
  - 1926-1927 (Box 42)
  - 1928 (Box 43)
- Disciplinary records, 1915-1920; Accession 1935-A-004
  - Volume with grades, cuts, class lists, chapel excuses, Sunday permission, warnings, quality points, omitted exams, failure in R.O.T.C., penalties for breaking probation, 1915-1920 (Box 1)
- Graphs of student grades, 1935-1936; Accession 1936-A-002
  - Graphs of student grades, 1935-1936 (Box AF1)
- Student room assignments, 1837-1939; Accession 1940-A-005
  - Room Assignments, 1837-1939
    - 1837-1847 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1842-1853 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1861-1874 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1905-1920 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1909-1915 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1910-1913 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1915-1920 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1920-1926 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1927-1928 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 1930-1931 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - 1933-1934 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - 1934-1937 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - 1935-1939 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Registration and course credit books, 1888-1901; Accession 1941-A-001
  - 1888-1889 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Elective courses - Classes of 1890-1891, 1889-1890 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - 1890-1891 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Elective courses, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1891-1892 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1892-1893 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Second term electives - Classes of 1893-1894 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Classes of 1894-1895, 1893-1894 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1894-1895 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1896-1897 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1897-1898 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1898-1899 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Electives, 1899-1900 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Electives, 1900-1901 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Record of cuts for fall term, Class of 1945W, Accession 1948-A-003
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2021
  - Record of cuts for fall term, Class of 1945W (Box AF5)
- Student grade books of Rollin Osterweiss for history courses, 1943-1944; Accession 1983-A-056
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2020
  - Student grade books of Rollin Osterweiss for Navy V-12 Freshman History and History of Sea Power and Elementary Strategy courses, 1943-1944 (Box 1)
- Student records, 1915-1948; Accession 1984-A-036
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023
  - Ledger with lists, 1915-1948
    - Lecture room schedules (Box 1)
    - Anticipatory and special exams
    - Commencement excuses
    - Late degrees
    - Vacation tenants
    - Students leaving college
- Yale College grade average charts for the Classes of 1942-1965, 1938-1965; Accession 2005-A-187
  - Yale College grade average charts for the Classes of 1942-1965, 1938-1965 (Box 1)